## **Melanie Rayner-Patton**

### **Data Analyst**

Data Analyst with 1 year of professional experience and 4 years of academic experience in the field. Graduated from Southern New Hampshire University with a BS in Computer Science and currently attending Old Dominion University's MS in Data Science & Analytics program, with projected graduation in Fall 2024. Certified by IBM as a Data Science Professional. Experience working with programming languages such as SQL and Python and building dashboards using Tableau. High level knowledge of data structures, web scraping, statistics and data analytics. A more technical role geared towards statistical analysis and data modeling is desired.

### **Work Experience**

#### **Data Operations Analyst**

#### Advantasure

January 2023 to Present

Conduct regular and ad hoc reporting for clients using SQL, Toad Data Point, Excel and Tableau. Ad hoc reporting facilitated using JIRA. Database warehouses utilized include Microsoft Oracle and Microsoft SQL Server Management System.

## Data Analyst Intern

#### **KVLR Capital**

October 2022 to January 2023

Compiled a database consisting of surgery centers from around the United States using the CMS website. Created a web scraper to gather missing information from Google Maps, such as business names and website URLs. Selenium Chrome Driver and Python were used to scrape Google Maps.

#### **Education**

## Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Southern New Hampshire University

February 2020 to June 2023

# Master of Science in Data Science and Analytics Old Dominion University

August 2023 to September 2024

#### **Certifications and Licenses**

#### **IBM Data Science Professional Certificate**

January 2022 to Present